Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we're talking about going out for a drink.
我是Kathryn，今天我们聊聊出去喝一杯的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to a bar and we're going to order cocktails.
我们要去酒吧点鸡尾酒。
So we're going to learn all about the different types of cocktails and a little bit more language
所以我们会学到各种鸡尾酒的类型，以及一些在酒吧能用到的语言。
that you can use at a bar.
在酒吧里能用到的。
Exactly.
正是。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
那我们来听听今天的对话吧。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿回来。
What can I get you?
您要点什么？
I'll have a Cosmo, please.
我要一杯大都会马提尼，谢谢。
Dude, you can't order a Cosmo.
哥们，你不能点大都会马提尼。
That's a ladies drink.
那是女士喝的酒。
You're embarrassing me.
你让我难堪了。
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢？
It's a good drink.
这酒挺好喝的。
It's too soft.
太淡了。
Order something with a little more kick to it.
点个劲儿大点的。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll have a Sex on the Beach.
我要一杯沙滩性爱。
You have got to be kidding me.
你是在逗我吧。
Come on.
别这样。
It's delicious.
这酒很好喝。
Especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
尤其是配上菠萝或椰子的时候。
Forget it.
算了。
I'm ordering for you.
我帮你点。
I'll have a Scotch on the Rocks and my friend here will have a Manhattan.
我要一杯加冰威士忌，我这位朋友要一杯曼哈顿。
Put it on my tab.
记在我账上。
Here.
给。
Now, this is a real drink.
这才叫真正的酒。
It's strong.
劲儿大。
This is going to get me wasted.
这能把我灌醉。
That's the idea.
就是要这样。
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now, let's take a look at some of those drinks on Language Takeaway.
现在，我们来看看“语言小贴士”环节里的一些酒名。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So in Language Takeaway today, we're going to focus on the names of drinks.
在今天的“语言小贴士”中，我们重点讲酒的名字。
So we heard four of them in today's dialogue.
我们在今天的对话里听到了四种酒。
What was that first one, Marco?
第一种是什么，Marco？
The first one was a Cosmo or also called a Cosmopolitan.
第一种是Cosmo，也叫大都会马提尼。
Okay.
好的。
So this is something if you watch the TV show Sex in the City, you will have heard before
如果你看过电视剧《欲望都市》，你应该听过这个，
because the girls always order Cosmos.
因为剧里的女孩们总点大都会马提尼。
Now, a Cosmopolitan is served in a martini glass, right?
大都会马提尼是用马提尼杯装的，对吧？
Right.
对。
You've seen the martini glass.
你见过马提尼杯。
It kind of looks like a triangle.
它看起来有点像三角形。
And it's very easy to spill.
而且很容易洒出来。
Yeah.
嗯。
That's right.
没错。
So what does a Cosmo have?
那么大都会马提尼里有什么？
Because obviously, a cocktail is a combination of different liquors or alcohol with maybe
因为显然，鸡尾酒是不同烈酒或酒精的混合，可能还加果汁之类的。
juices and stuff like that.
果汁之类的。
So what does a Cosmo have?
那么大都会马提尼里有什么？
That's a good question.
问得好。
Cosmo is a vodka drink, I believe, and it's served in a martini glass.
大都会马提尼是伏特加调的酒，我记得，用马提尼杯装。
But it's generally considered a drink for ladies, for women.
但通常被认为是女士喝的酒。
Why is that?
为什么？
Probably because it's a weaker drink, but also because it's popular in the media and
可能是因为它度数低，也因为它在媒体和电影里常被塑造成女性饮品。
in movies and stuff as a women's drink.
在媒体和电影里。
So that's how it got that reputation.
所以就有了这个名声。
I see.
我明白了。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So that's what a Cosmo is.
这就是大都会马提尼。
And now we move on to another very popular drink, a little bit more tropical.
现在我们来说另一种很流行的酒，更热带风味的。
I think everyone always has it when the Caribbean or when they're on vacation at the beach.
我觉得大家去加勒比海或海边度假时总会点它。
It's called a Sex on the Beach.
它叫沙滩性爱。
Okay.
好的。
This name might make you laugh because Sex on the Beach, it's very descriptive, but it's
这个名字可能会让你笑，因为沙滩性爱，很形象，但它其实是很常见的酒。
actually a very common drink.
很常见的酒。
And in the dialogue, he talks about how he likes to have this drink served in a pineapple
在对话里，他提到喜欢用菠萝或椰子来装这杯酒。
or a coconut.
用菠萝或椰子。
So that means it's very fruity.
所以说明它果味很浓。
And I think it's a rum drink, right?
我觉得它是朗姆酒调的，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
And it usually has either coconut juice in it or maybe some pineapple juice.
它通常加椰子汁或菠萝汁。
Very fruity.
果味很浓。
I think they add a little bit of vanilla or even ice cream or milk or something like that.
我觉得他们加了一点香草，甚至冰淇淋或牛奶之类的东西。
So it's very fruity.
所以果味很浓。
It's kind of like a milkshake with liquor.
有点像加了酒的奶昔。
Weird.
奇怪。
Yeah.
是啊。
I don't know that I've ever had one, but this is the part of the dialogue where his
我不知道我有没有喝过，但这是对话中他
friend says, come on, you need to buy something that's more manly.
朋友说：“拜托，你得买点更爷们儿的东西。”
He orders a Scotch on the rocks instead.
他改点了一杯加冰苏格兰威士忌。
Okay.
好的。
So a Scotch is a type of liquor.
所以苏格兰威士忌是一种酒。
It's a whiskey.
它是一种威士忌。
That's right.
没错。
Scotch whiskey comes from Scotland and it's a whiskey drink.
苏格兰威士忌来自苏格兰，是一种威士忌饮品。
And basically, Scotch on the rocks means Scotch poured over ice.
基本上，加冰苏格兰威士忌就是苏格兰威士忌倒在冰块上。
Ice.
冰块。
So, in this case, rocks means ice.
所以，在这里，“rocks”指的是冰块。
And you'll hear this often.
你经常能听到这个说法。
Do you want that on the rocks?
你要加冰的吗？
Do you want that on ice?
Right.
对。
So you don't say, I want whiskey with ice or you don't say, I want Scotch with ice.
所以你不会说“我要威士忌加冰”或“我要苏格兰威士忌加冰”。
You can just say on the rocks.
你直接说“on the rocks”就行。
Scotch on the rocks.
加冰苏格兰威士忌。
So it may be if you're ordering a rum drink and you don't want it mixed with anything,
所以如果你点朗姆酒，不想掺任何东西，
you can say rum on the rocks.
你可以说“朗姆酒加冰”。
On the rocks.
加冰。
Very good.
很好。
And not only are we ordering a Scotch on the rocks, but we're also ordering a Manhattan.
我们不仅点了加冰苏格兰威士忌，还点了一杯曼哈顿。
So what does a Manhattan have?
那么曼哈顿里面有什么？
All right.
好了。
A Manhattan is a very strong cocktail.
曼哈顿是一种非常烈的鸡尾酒。
It has bourbon, which is a kind of whiskey.
它含有波本威士忌，这是一种威士忌。
It's an American whiskey.
它是一种美国威士忌。
It has vermouth, which is also a very strong ingredient.
它含有味美思，这也是一种很烈的成分。
It has bitters.
它含有苦精。
What is bitters?
什么是苦精？
Bitters is another kind of ingredient that is often used in cocktails to make things
苦精是另一种常用于鸡尾酒的成分，用来让饮品
bitter.
变苦。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
So it's not a sweet drink.
所以它不是甜饮料。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
It's not a sweet drink.
它不是甜饮料。
Although they sometimes put a little bit of lemon or orange rind in the drink and that's
虽然他们有时会在饮料里放一点柠檬皮或橙皮，那是
the skin of the orange.
橙子的外皮。
Okay.
好的。
So both these drinks are pretty strong.
所以这两种饮料都挺烈的。
They're very interesting though.
不过它们很有趣。
All the ones that we've seen, the Cosmo, the Sex on the Beach, they're all called cocktails.
我们见过的所有那些，比如大都会、沙滩性爱，都叫鸡尾酒。
And a cocktail has the characteristic that it usually has alcohol, right?
鸡尾酒的特点是通常含有酒精，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So cocktail is a mix of different ingredients, but it's an alcohol-based drink.
所以鸡尾酒是不同成分的混合，但它是基于酒精的饮品。
Okay.
好的。
You can also get non-alcoholic cocktails.
你也可以点无酒精鸡尾酒。
So there is that option.
所以有这个选择。
All right.
好了。
Very good.
很好。
So why don't we take a break?
那我们休息一下怎么样？
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
让我们再听一遍对话，稍后回来进行流利度训练。
What can I get you?
您要点什么？
I'll have a Cosmo, please.
我要一杯大都会，谢谢。
Dude, you can't order a Cosmo.
哥们儿，你不能点大都会。
That's a ladies drink.
那是女士喝的酒。
You're embarrassing me.
你让我难堪了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊？
It's a good drink.
这酒不错啊。
It's too soft.
太淡了。
Order something with a little more kick to it.
点个更有劲儿的。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll have a Sex on the Beach.
我要一杯沙滩性爱。
You have got to be kidding me.
你是在跟我开玩笑吧。
Come on.
拜托。
It's delicious.
它很好喝。
Especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
尤其是配上菠萝或椰子的时候。
Forget it.
算了。
I'm ordering for you.
我帮你点。
I'll have a Scotch on the Rocks and my friend here will have a Manhattan.
我要一杯加冰苏格兰威士忌，我这位朋友要一杯曼哈顿。
Put it on my tab.
记在我账上。
Here.
给。
Now, this is a real drink.
这才叫真正的酒。
That's strong.
这酒劲儿真大。
This is going to get me wasted.
这杯下去我肯定要喝醉了。
That's the idea.
就是要这个效果。
All right.
好吧。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now, let's talk a little bit more about these drinks on Fluency Builder.
现在，在“流利度构建”环节，我们来多聊聊这些饮品。
So Marco, there are many different ways to talk about drinks but the most important ones
所以Marco，谈论饮品有很多不同的方式，但最重要的
that we often discuss, especially with cocktails, is weak drinks versus strong drinks.
我们经常讨论的，尤其是鸡尾酒，就是淡酒和烈酒的区别。
That's right.
没错。
Weak drinks versus strong drinks.
淡酒和烈酒。
Usually, the Cosmo or maybe the Sex on the Beach, it's considered to be a weak drink.
通常，像大都会鸡尾酒或者性海滩鸡尾酒，被认为是淡酒。
That's right.
没错。
So it's not very strong because there's less alcohol.
所以它们不太烈，因为酒精含量少。
Like a Cosmo has fruit juice, like cranberry juice, and the Sex on the Beach is very fruity
比如大都会鸡尾酒里有果汁，像蔓越莓汁，而性海滩鸡尾酒果味很浓，
so it makes it less alcoholy.
所以酒精味没那么重。
That's right.
没错。
And actually, those two also have one type of alcohol.
而且实际上，这两种酒也只含一种酒精。
So it's not very strong.
所以它们不太烈。
Whereas, maybe a Manhattan has all this mix of bourbon and other drinks as well so it'll
而像曼哈顿鸡尾酒，混合了波本威士忌和其他酒，所以
be a strong alcoholic drink.
会是烈性酒。
Yeah.
是的。
And Scotch on the Rocks is also very strong because it's just scotch.
而加冰苏格兰威士忌也很烈，因为它就是纯苏格兰威士忌。
Right.
对。
You're not mixing it with anything.
你没加任何东西混合。
No.
没有。
There's just some ice and some scotch.
就只有一些冰块和苏格兰威士忌。
So that's a strong drink.
所以那是烈酒。
Okay.
好的。
So obviously, his friend was saying that all those drinks are too weak.
所以很明显，他朋友说那些酒都太淡了。
He should order something with a little more kick to it.
他应该点一些更有劲儿的。
So in this context, kick means strength.
所以在这个语境下，“kick”指的是烈度。
So alcohol.
也就是酒精。
He wants a drink that's not weak, that's strong.
他想要一杯不淡的、烈的酒。
So a strong drink has more kick than a weak drink.
所以烈酒比淡酒更有劲儿。
So can we use this with food or with other situations?
那这个词可以用在食物或其他场合吗？
You can, but with food, it usually means spice.
可以，但用在食物上，通常指的是辣味。
So Indian food tends to have a lot of kick to it.
所以印度菜通常很有劲儿。
That means it's very spicy.
意思是它很辣。
Okay.
好的。
So with alcohol, it's strong.
所以用在酒上，是烈。
With food, it's usually spicy.
用在食物上，通常是辣。
If this rice has a kick to it, it means it's a little spicy.
如果这米饭有股劲儿，意思是它有点辣。
That's right.
没错。
So just think about kick as meaning that something is strong or has a strong flavor.
所以就把“kick”理解为某物很烈或味道很冲。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, when they were ordering, they didn't pay immediately because she said, put it on
现在，他们点单时没有马上付钱，因为她说了“记在我的账上”。
my tab.
好的。
All right.
所以“put something on a tab”，这在你去酒吧或餐厅点酒时非常重要。
So to put something on a tab, this is really important when you're going to a bar or a
restaurant and you want to order drinks.
一个“tab”就是你不立即支付的账单。
A tab is a bill that you don't pay immediately.
The bartender will write down all of the drinks that you have and all of their prices and
酒保会记下你点的所有酒水和价格，
you pay when you leave.
你离开时再付钱。
Okay.
好的。
So if you put something on your tab, you'll pay it later or when you leave.
所以如果你把东西记在账上，你会稍后或离开时再付。
That's right.
没错。
So normally at a bar in America, you say, I want to start a tab.
所以通常在美国的酒吧，你会说“我想开个账”。
That means I want to start a bill and you give the bartender your credit card and he
意思是我想开始一个账单，你把信用卡给酒保，
will keep your credit card until you leave.
他会保管你的信用卡直到你离开。
Oh really?
哦，真的吗？
So he keeps your credit card until you leave because obviously maybe you start a tab and
所以他保管你的信用卡直到你离开，因为显然，如果你开了账，
then you want to leave and you don't want to pay then it's a problem.
然后想走却不付钱，那就麻烦了。
Or people get a little bit drunk and they forget they have to pay.
或者人们喝得有点醉，忘了要付钱。
So bartenders now keep your credit card so that even if you forget to pay, they can charge
所以现在酒保会保管你的信用卡，这样即使你忘了付钱，他们也能
you.
扣款。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
Okay.
好的。
Very interesting.
真有意思。
And now for our last phrase, he was a little bit concerned because this drink is so strong.
现在，关于最后一个短语，他有点担心，因为这杯酒太烈了。
He said, this is going to get me wasted.
他说：“这杯下去我肯定要喝醉了。”
Okay.
好的。
So to be wasted or to get wasted means to get very, very drunk.
所以“be wasted”或“get wasted”意思是喝得非常非常醉。
To drink too much.
喝太多了。
So if you say I'm wasted, it means I'm very drunk.
所以如果你说“I'm wasted”，意思是我很醉了。
I'm very drunk.
我很醉了。
You could say, oh, look at those, those boys over there.
你可以说，哦，看那边那些男孩。
They're all wasted.
他们都喝醉了。
They're all, you know, being drunk and sick and yeah.
他们都，你知道，醉醺醺的，难受的样子，嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a very informal, very casual kind of a colloquial way of saying being drunk
所以这是一种非常非正式、非常随意、口语化的说法，表示喝醉了。
or being intoxicated.
或者喝醉了。
That's right.
没错。
So it's, it's something we often use with friends or as you know, with young people,
所以我们经常和朋友或年轻人用这个词，
but it's not something you want to use in your English class because it's not a good
但你在英语课上不想用它，因为这不是什么好事。
thing to be.
喝醉不是好事。
It's not a good thing to be wasted.
喝得烂醉不是好事。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So now let's take a break and listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to
现在我们休息一下，再听一遍对话，然后回来继续聊。
talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
What can I get you?
您要点什么？
I'll have a Cosmo, please.
我要一杯大都会鸡尾酒。
Dude, you can't order a Cosmo.
哥们，你不能点大都会。
That's a ladies drink.
那是女士喝的酒。
You're embarrassing me.
你让我难堪了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It's a good drink.
这酒挺好喝的。
It's too soft.
太淡了。
Order something with a little more kick to it.
点个劲儿大点的。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll have a sex on the beach.
我要一杯沙滩性爱。
You have got to be kidding me.
你是在开玩笑吧。
Come on.
拜托。
It's delicious.
这酒很好喝。
Especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
尤其是配上菠萝或椰子的时候。
Forget it.
算了。
I'm ordering for you.
我帮你点。
I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a Manhattan.
我要一杯加冰威士忌，我朋友要一杯曼哈顿。
Put it on my tab.
记在我账上。
Here.
给。
Now this is a real drink.
这才是真正的酒。
That's strong.
这酒劲儿大。
This is going to get me wasted.
这能让我喝得烂醉。
That's the idea.
就是这个意思。
All right.
好了。
So about cocktails, liquors, what is your favorite cocktail when you go out?
那么关于鸡尾酒和烈酒，你出去喝的时候最喜欢的鸡尾酒是什么？
I almost always order gin and tonic.
我几乎总是点金汤力。
That's my cocktail.
那是我的招牌酒。
So gin is another type of liquor?
所以金酒是另一种烈酒？
That's right.
没错。
Gin is another type of liquor like vodka or whiskey.
金酒是另一种烈酒，像伏特加或威士忌一样。
It has a very unique taste.
它有很独特的味道。
And tonic is a kind of water but it has a certain flavor to it.
汤力水是一种水，但带有某种风味。
It has a flavor to it.
它有独特的风味。
So gin and tonic usually has some gin, some tonic water and some lime.
所以金汤力通常包含一些金酒、一些汤力水和一些青柠。
But the tonic water is kind of bubbly.
但汤力水有点气泡感。
That's right.
没错。
It's bubbly.
它有气泡。
I like bubbly drinks.
我喜欢有气泡的饮料。
So you like champagne and stuff like that.
所以你喜欢香槟之类的。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
I see.
我明白了。
What's your favorite?
你最喜欢什么？
I am a whiskey guy and so I usually order something like this scotch on the rocks.
我是个威士忌爱好者，所以我通常点像加冰威士忌这样的酒。
I never like to mix it with anything else.
我从来不喜欢加其他东西。
And especially I really don't like having sweet drinks.
尤其是我真的不喜欢喝甜饮料。
So you're a purist.
所以你是个纯粹主义者。
Kind of.
算是吧。
It's just that when the sweet alcohol and things that are sweet, I don't really think
只是甜酒和甜的东西，
go that well together.
我觉得不太搭。
No, I think I agree.
不，我同意。
Although there are some sweet alcohols.
虽然也有一些甜酒。
Our Italian friends will be familiar with limoncello.
我们的意大利朋友会熟悉柠檬甜酒。
It's a dessert liqueur which tastes like lemon.
这是一种餐后甜酒，味道像柠檬。
Or also Kahlua which is very sweet.
或者还有非常甜的卡鲁瓦咖啡酒。
It's a coffee alcohol, right?
这是一种咖啡酒，对吧？
Right.
对。
So many people like to put Kahlua in their coffee to have Irish coffee.
所以很多人喜欢把卡鲁瓦咖啡酒加进咖啡里，做成爱尔兰咖啡。
That's right.
没错。
And actually the alcoholic world is very vast and actually many people don't drink alcohol.
实际上，酒的世界非常广阔，而且很多人不喝酒。
Many people may have it occasionally.
很多人可能偶尔喝一点。
But the other interesting thing is that usually countries have a national alcoholic drink.
但另一个有趣的事情是，通常每个国家都有一种国民酒。
So for example, the Mexican national alcoholic drink would be tequila.
比如，墨西哥的国民酒是龙舌兰。
That's right.
没错。
Or Russian or Eastern European, vodka.
或者俄罗斯或东欧是伏特加。
So in your country, maybe you have a local or a national alcoholic drink we would be
所以在你的国家，也许有一种本地或国民酒，
very interested to know about.
我们很想知道。
That's right.
没错。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
All right guys.
好了，各位。
See you.
再见。
Bye.
拜拜。